<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Simone Paci</title>
    <link>https://SimonePaci.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Simone Paci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Simone Paci</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Nation-Building Through War: Piedmont and the Unification of Italy</title>
      <link>https://SimonePaci.github.io/project/piedmont-sambanis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://SimonePaci.github.io/project/piedmont-sambanis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 9th, 1855, upon disembarking at the Crimean port of Balaklava, General Enrico Cialdini might have wondered what had brought him and other eighteen-thousand Piedmontese troops so far from their home-port of Genoa. Why would the small Kingdom of Sardinia care to join a war between England, France, and the Russian Empire? The General probably did not make the connection six years later, when he seized control of Naples in the name of Vittorio Emanuele II, completing the first (though still partial) unification of the peninsula since Ancient Roman times. Soon thereafter, Vittorio Emanuele II would be proclaimed ruler of the newborn Kingdom of Italy. To Cialdini’s credit, students of political science have spent countless pages trying to unravel the complex dynamics of nation-building and yet no satisfactory full picture has emerged. Our paper joins these efforts and seeks to complete previous accounts, exploring a novel perspective on the interaction between international and domestic spheres.&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The Micro-History of Italy&#39;s WWI Military Casualties</title>
      <link>https://SimonePaci.github.io/project/caduti-wwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://SimonePaci.github.io/project/caduti-wwi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project concerns&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
